<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jacopo Donati</title>
    <link>https://www.jacopodonati.it/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jacopo Donati</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>it-it</language>
    <copyright>© 2020-2022 Jacopo Donati</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 07:39:51 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.jacopodonati.it/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vita transcurrit</title>
      <link>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/vita-transcurrit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 07:39:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/vita-transcurrit/</guid>
      <description>Dum differtur, vita transcurrit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be a good one</title>
      <link>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/be-a-good-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2022 08:50:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/be-a-good-one/</guid>
      <description>Whatever you are, be a good one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part of the dance</title>
      <link>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/part-of-the-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 08:45:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/part-of-the-dance/</guid>
      <description>You can do it like it’s a great weight, or you can do it like it’s part of the dance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A built language</title>
      <link>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/a-built-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 09:26:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/a-built-language/</guid>
      <description>A relationship is about inventing your own language. You’ve got the jokes, you’ve got the songs, you have this anecdote that’s going to make you laugh three years later. It’s this language that you build. That’s what you mourn for when you’re losing someone you love. This language you’re not going to speak with anybody else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Until it&#39;s sold</title>
      <link>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/until-its-sold/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 09:42:36 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/until-its-sold/</guid>
      <description>There is no art until it&amp;rsquo;s on paper, there is no art until it&amp;rsquo;s sold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alt-Wien war einmal neu</title>
      <link>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/alt-wien/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 08:56:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/alt-wien/</guid>
      <description>Ich muß den Ästheten eine niederschmetternde Mitteilung machen: Alt-Wien war einmal neu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live in it</title>
      <link>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/live-in-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 10:04:38 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/live-in-it/</guid>
      <description>I’m not telling you to make the world better, because I don’t think that progress is necessarily part of the package.
I’m just telling you to live in it. Not just to endure it, not just to suffer it, not just to pass through it, but to live in it. To look at it. To try to get the picture. To live recklessly. To take chances. To make your own work and take pride in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trollope</title>
      <link>https://www.jacopodonati.it/consigli-non-richiesti/trollope/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 17:13:20 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacopodonati.it/consigli-non-richiesti/trollope/</guid>
      <description>Gli aspiranti scrittori si posizionano sempre su uno spettro che a un&amp;rsquo;estremità vede coloro che scrivono tantissimo ma non editano abbastanza, mentre all&amp;rsquo;estremo opposto ci sono coloro che a un certo punto si bloccano. Ai grafomani non ho molto da consigliare. Per gli altri, però, un consiglio ce l&amp;rsquo;ho: il metodo Trollope.
Per tutta la vita Trollope ritagliò del tempo per scrivere ogni mattina prima di andare a lavorare. In trentotto anni ha scritto 47 romanzi, 18 saggi, 12 racconti, e 2 opere teatrali citation needed, e il suo metodo era molto semplice: 250 parole ogni quarto d&amp;rsquo;ora.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scadenze</title>
      <link>https://www.jacopodonati.it/consigli-non-richiesti/scadenze/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 17:09:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacopodonati.it/consigli-non-richiesti/scadenze/</guid>
      <description>Datti delle scadenze. Scrivi come se il non rispettarle potrebbe farti perdere il lavoro. (perché è così.)
È probabile che ciò che scriverai farà schifo (v. the gap). L&amp;rsquo;unico modo per migliorare è scrivere. Scrivere tanto. Ma tanto tanto. E l&amp;rsquo;unico modo per riuscire a farlo è disciplinarsi, porsi dei traguardi (un racconto a settimana? 1.000 parole al giorno?) e fare di tutto per rispettarli.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your taste</title>
      <link>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/your-taste/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 11:18:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/your-taste/</guid>
      <description>Nobody tells this to people who are beginners, I wish someone told me.
All of us who do creative work, we get into it because we have good taste. But there is this gap. For the first couple years you make stuff, it’s just not that good. It’s trying to be good, it has potential, but it’s not. But your taste, the thing that got you into the game, is still killer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life is daring adventure</title>
      <link>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/life-is-daring-adventure/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 08:37:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/life-is-daring-adventure/</guid>
      <description>Life is either daring adventure or nothing at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Try something</title>
      <link>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/try-something/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 08:37:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/try-something/</guid>
      <description>Above all, try something.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leggi</title>
      <link>https://www.jacopodonati.it/consigli-non-richiesti/leggete/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 09:13:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacopodonati.it/consigli-non-richiesti/leggete/</guid>
      <description>Leggi. Tanto.
E leggi bene. La lettura per lavoro non è quella in cui semplicemente ci si perde in un mondo fittizioma quella in cui una corda di sicurezza ci tiene ancorati al mondo vigile. Devi poter ragionare sul testo, sulle scelte lessicali, sulla struttura narrativa, sui personaggi, sui dialoghi…
E un corso di scrittura può aiutare a sviluppare consapevolezza, ma non può insegnare molto altro. Il resto va sviluppato attraverso la lettura.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t fight them. Don&#39;t waste your time</title>
      <link>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/don-t-waste-your-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 08:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/don-t-waste-your-time/</guid>
      <description>I: You have some wonderful stories of basically getting away with stuff at the studios.
MB: I’d learned one very simple trick: say yes. Simply say yes. Like Joseph E. Levine, on The Producers, said, “The curly-haired guy—he’s funny looking. Fire him.” He wanted me to fire Gene Wilder. And I said, “Yes, he’s gone. I’m firing him.” I never did. But he forgot. After the screening of Blazing Saddles, the head of Warner Bros.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t fight them. Don&#39;t waste your time</title>
      <link>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/err-kindness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 08:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/err-kindness/</guid>
      <description>Err in the direction of kindness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life shrinks</title>
      <link>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/life-shrinks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 08:11:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/life-shrinks/</guid>
      <description>Life shrinks or expands in proportion to one’s courage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>the world is movement</title>
      <link>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/the-world-is-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 11:00:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/the-world-is-movement/</guid>
      <description>For the world is movement, and you cannot be stationary in your attitude toward something that is moving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corsi di scrittura</title>
      <link>https://www.jacopodonati.it/consigli-non-richiesti/corso-di-scrittura/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 09:58:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacopodonati.it/consigli-non-richiesti/corso-di-scrittura/</guid>
      <description>Se pensi che ti manchino le basi, fai un corso di scrittura. Non deve necessariamente essere un corso costoso, né particolarmente lungo.
Se non sei convinto dell&amp;rsquo;efficacia di un corso di scrittura, parti da qualcosa di semplice, ma se ti rendi conto di aver frequentato più di due o tre corsi di scrittura, prendi coscienza che non li stai facendo per imparare a scrivere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>L&#39;istinto</title>
      <link>https://www.jacopodonati.it/consigli-non-richiesti/istinto/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 09:58:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacopodonati.it/consigli-non-richiesti/istinto/</guid>
      <description>Impara a fidarti quando il tuo istinto suggerisce che ciò che hai scritto non funziona. E impara a fidarti quando una persona (una qualsiasi persona) ti dice che qualcosa non funziona: con ogni probabilità non sarà quello che ti indica il vero problema, ma è altrettanto probabile che lì ci sia un problema da risolvere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scheda di lettura</title>
      <link>https://www.jacopodonati.it/consigli-non-richiesti/schede-di-lettura/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 09:58:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacopodonati.it/consigli-non-richiesti/schede-di-lettura/</guid>
      <description>Se hai un manoscritto che desideri migliorare ma non sai da che parte cominciare, cerca qualcuno che ti faccia una scheda di lettura. Chiedi a chi offre servizi editoriali a privati, o chiedila a un&amp;rsquo;agenzia letteraria.
La dovrai pagare e costerà più di quanto pensi, ma avrai una base di partenza su cui ragionare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>there you are, still yourself, with your particular way of loving</title>
      <link>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/with-your-particular-way-of-loving/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 09:12:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jacopodonati.it/manuale-per-vivere/with-your-particular-way-of-loving/</guid>
      <description>We want to believe that love is singular and exclusive, and it unnerves us to think that it might actually be renewable and somewhat repetitive in its habits. Would your current partner ever call his or her new partner by the same pet name he/she uses for you, once you are dead and buried? Well, why not? There are only so many pet names. Why should that bother you? Well, because you believe it is you, in particular, who is loved (that is why dear Ed calls you “honey-bunny”), but no: love just is, and you happened to be in the path of it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
